newlifejournal.org 2016-06-23

# Flavors.me : Privacy policy

## Flavors.me privacy policy

### Moo Print Limited (“Moo Print”, “Us” or "We") are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

Last updated 2 September 2013 

This policy (together with our terms of use [Terms of Use](https://flavors.me/terms) and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the “Act”), the data controller is Moo Print Limited (registered in England and Wales with company number: 05121723) of 32-38 Scrutton Street London EC2A 4RQ Information we may collect from you

You can browse our website without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself. Once you create an account, which only requires that you provide us a login name, email address and password, you are not anonymous to us. If you choose to provide us with this or any other personal information, you consent to the processing, storage and transfer of that information.

We collect, use and share personally identifiable information and non-personally identifiable information only as described in this privacy policy. By providing us with your information and registering on the website, you agree to the collection of such information.

### We may collect and process the following data about you:

  * Payment Information. If you decide to upgrade we will either collect payment information or link you to a website where you can make payment;

  * Login information. We recommend that you use a username as your login name in order to protect your own privacy. If you use your name as a login, or otherwise provide your name or other information in your community profile or bio, the information will become available to us and the community and may be used to contact you;

  * Log files. When you use our website, our servers automatically record certain information sent by your web browser. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, browser type, referring / exit pages and URLs, number of clicks and how you interact with links on our website, domain names, landing pages, pages viewed, mobile carrier, and other such information;

  * Clear gifs information. When you use our website, we may employ clear gifs (also known as web beacons), which are used to track the online usage patterns. The information is used to enable more accurate reporting and make our website better for members of our community.

  * Information about your actual location, like GPS signals sent by a mobile device. We may also use various technologies to determine location. When you use our website by or through a mobile device, we may access, collect, monitor and/or remotely store “location data,” which may include GPS coordinates (e.g. latitude and/or longitude) or similar information regarding the location of your mobile device. Location data may convey to us information about how you browse our website. Though location data does not collect or share any personally identifiable information about you, it may be used in conjunction with personally identifiable information from other sources. Some features of our website, particularly location-based services, may not function properly if use or availability of location data is impaired or disabled.

  * Device identifiers. When you access our website by or through a mobile device, we may access, collect, monitor and/or remotely store one or more “device identifiers.” Device identifiers are small data files or similar data structures stored on or associated with your mobile device, which uniquely identify your mobile device and are used to enhance our website. A device identifier may be data stored in connection with the device hardware, data stored in connection with the device’s operating system or other software, or data sent by us to the device. A device identifier may convey to us information about how you use our website. Though a device identifier does not collect or share any personally identifiable information about you, it may be used in conjunction with personally identifiable information obtained from other sources. A device identifier may remain persistently on your device, to help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through our website. Some features of our website may not function properly if use or availability of device identifiers are impaired or disabled. Our website may access, collect and/or store device identifiers.

  * Third party tools. We use third party analytics tools, such as Google Analytics, to help understand the use of our website. Many of these tools collect the information sent by your browser as part of a web page request, including cookies and your IP address. These analytics tools also receive this information and their use of it is governed by their privacy policy.

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms when using or registering to use our website, subscribing to our services, posting material or requesting further services. We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with the website;

  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence;

  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them; and

  * Device-specific information (such as your hardware model, operating system version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information).

### Cookies

We also collect non-personally identifying information related to your use of our website. When you use our website, we may send one or more “cookies” – a small data file – to your computer to uniquely identify your browser and let us help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the site. A cookie may convey to us anonymous information about how you browse our website, and we may use such information to address targeted advertising such as banner ads or other communications to you. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive after you close your browser so that your browser can use it on subsequent visits to our website. Persistent cookies can be removed by following your web browser’s directions. A session cookie is temporary and disappears after you close your browser. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some features of our website may not function properly if the ability to accept cookies is disabled.

### Where we store your personal data

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy. 

### Public posts

Our website provides you with a variety of methods to communicate with others, through public forums like your web site, community profile information and direct messaging. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them.

### Information security

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of the website, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) on or through our website, we encrypt the transmission of that information using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology. We require third parties such as PayPal to encrypt this information as well.

We also use commercially reasonable physical, managerial, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your personal information, once we receive it. No method of electronic transmission of storage is 100% secure, however, and we cannot ensure or warrant the absolute security of any information you transmit or store using our website.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to the Website; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

### Uses Made of the Information

We use information held about you in the following ways:

we may use your email address to send you information about Flavors and/or Moo Print and its features, member communications, surveys and newsletters. If you opt in, we will send you marketing communications regarding Flavors and other companies we believe would be of interest to you. We will not sell or rent your personal information to third parties for their marketing purposes without your explicit consent. If you opt in for marketing communications you can always let us know if you want to opt-out of receiving those messages;

we use information we collect to operate, maintain and provide you the features and functionality of Flavors, to analyse how our website is used, diagnose service or technical problems, maintain security, personalize content, remember information to help you efficiently access your account, aggregate and monitor relevant metrics, including but not necessarily limited to the total number of visitors, traffic, and demographic patterns;

if you choose to use our invitation service to invite a friend to Flavors, we will ask you for that person’s email address and automatically send an email invitation. We store this information to send this email, to register your friend if your invitation is accepted, and to track the success of our invitation service. If you utilize a social media application to perform the invitation, we will receive the information directly from the social media service and maintain that information.

behavioral information: We may display targeted advertisements to you while you are on and off our website based on information we obtain from you, about you and/or from third parties.

we allow Ad Serving Networks to display targeted advertisements to you while you are on and off our website based on information about you, as well as behavioural information and information obtained from third parties. Behavioural information is information about you that is collected based on your on-line activities, for example, the URLs you visit and searches you perform.

you may opt-out of targeted advertising at any time by exercising your choice by clicking [here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/). Please note that although this will opt you out of targeted advertising from the Ad Serving Networks we work with, you will continue to see advertisements, however these advertisements may not be as relevant to you as targeted ones.

we provide your information to a variety of service providers who assist us in providing you with the information and services you are requesting from us. These service providers may include credit card companies, computer hosting services and email communication companies. We have agreements with service providers which provide that your information can only be used in connection with providing services for us and for you.

as we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings. Customers, email, and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer or assign such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution or discussions regarding same.

we may share your information with a third party application with your consent, for example when you choose to access Flavors through such an application. We are not responsible for what those parties do with your information, so you should make sure you trust the application and that it has a privacy policy that is acceptable to you.

to ensure that the website and their content are presented in the most effective manner for you and for your mobile device or computer;

to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;

to analyse the ways in which you use the website to ensure you get the best experience;

to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so; and

to notify you about changes to our service.

We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to our advertisers, but we may provide them with aggregate information about our users. We may also use such aggregate information to help advertisers reach the kind of audience they want to target. We may make use of the personal data we have collected from you to enable us to comply with our advertisers' wishes by displaying their advertisement to that target audience.

### Disclosure of Your Information

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties: in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets; in order to obtain analytics information which helps us to provide you with a good experience when you visit our website and also allows us to improve our website; if Moo Print or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets; and If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Moo Print, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

The data we disclose to third parties in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside of the European Economic Area ("EEA").

### Your Rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [privacy@flavors.me](mailto:privacy@flavors.me). 

The website may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, advertisers and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### Access to Information

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of £10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

### Changes to Our Privacy Policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

### Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [privacy@flavors.me](mailto:privacy@flavors.me)
